this is going to be an epic view oh
Gosh this place is just absolutely
gorgeous oh Gosh get me out of here if you were
wondering what is the best free thing to do in
London today I'm going to show you one of my
personal favorites depending on what website
you look at apparently this is the most popular
free thing and visited place to go in London so
we are outside the iconic amazing Natural History
Museum here in South Kensington and I'm going to
take you along it is about 5 minutes to 10
on a Saturday morning we are rope dropping
guys we are not playing games look at this queue
hopefully we'll get in quite quickly hello guys
and if you're new to my channel hi I'm Hannah I
live in London and I like to do touristy things
I like to go shopping I like to go shopping a lot
um go to different restaurants and take you along
with me so make sure you are subscribed because
this is the first episode of many two a week in
all of March into April we'll see how we get on
where I'm doing two videos a week on a countdown
to Easter countdown to Spring eager for Easter
I'm not sure what we're going to call it okay
first learn of the day you need to have a ticket
booked which has blown my mind because this was
not a thing but hopefully we don't have to wait
too long it's free but yeah when I looked there's
like nothing for quite a few days so not the most
spontaneous of trips nearly there we waited about
10 minutes which I don't think is too bad yeah
that was only 10 minutes but do try and book it
I didn't even think to book I think I've become
a bit too much of a spontaneous Londoner I didn't
even think but we're in and we're going to go to
the dinosaur section but can we just appreciate
this building it's absolutely stunning inside
and out it's nearly 150 years old this reminds
me of being a kid oh my God don't worry I'm
not going to bore you too much with history
cuz let's be honest I don't really know it but
we're just going to go around here like you're
with me we're going to come on a little tour the
camera is not going to do that Justice the scale
is incredible there used to be a dinosaur on the
floor here when I was a kid I think I think the
dino is in the dinosaur section but yes this
is absolutely incredible and there are many
different sections and they're all colorcoded so
we're going to go to this purpley blue section
which is the dinosaurs and yeah I'm just going
to show you all the things that I like about this
place it is about 12 minutes past 10 let's see
how busy it is we did lose out a little bit on
the queuing there but this building it reminds
me of The Chemical Brothers video remember hey
boy hey girl that was filmed here I'm going to
try and show you like the best of what I think
is the best of oh it's dark in here I guess to
protect Theos so this has been here for many
years it's free to see I could imagine there's a
bit of a queue on a Saturday afternoon for like
I'm an animal kingdom that's so cool there's a
few screaming children it's proba be quite scary
actually now come on guys what Vlog is going to
show you a replica T-Rex animal atronic within
the first 5 minutes 5 minutes I don't know I
think that deserves a thumbs up make sure you
give this video a thumbs up if you enjoy and of
course there are some replica things as well you
can kind of learn about the history obviously of
dinosaurs oh my gosh look at those teeth that's
wild and then there's a whole section on Horns
I'm not going to tell you all the info on the
dinosaurs mainly cuz I can't actually pronounce
some of them what was that aoan gurus don't know
it's much bigger than than me no oh look at this
wow was that like an anatomy of what what kind of
dinosaur is that an alator albow saurus kind of
makes me feel a bit funny it's so clever how do
they know wow oh my gosh look at that hand that is
terrifying and the thumb it says was a spike ew my
God that's definitely giving Jurassic Park that
one okay there's a there's a gap in people guys
it is busy in here only a few minutes after
opening oh wow you can kind of understand why
so yeah they have these models there are some bits
which are real some of them that aren't and they
do have these signs every so often showing you
look up and then they have these little models
up the top there yeah they're not all real they
are cast made for the museums but there obviously
are quite a lot of real bones and things on
display here which is absolutely incredible look
at this one it what in the heck got Iguanodon oh
I should know how to say that come on I've been on
dinosaur oh my gosh the
camera is not going to do this
Justice look at the shadow that's so cool I mean
they're not real but they're meant to be from 150
million years ago made me feel very young oh wow
that's amazing yeah a lot of this is cast but you
know what it's given you a very good example
of what it would look like oh wow look at this
I really like the Shadows it's very atmospheric
in here but yes a lot of this is obviously cast
from um what they found in the ground oh my
gosh it's huge it's making me feel very very
short okay that was my Speedy tour of the
dinosaur area museums are very difficult to
Vlog and I don't know all the info as I'm sure
you've guessed but there are so many sections
here so we got to get on with it guys I think
this might be the noisiest busiest craziest
place I have ever vlogged so something I always
find when I come to some of the museums is it
makes me realize how dependent on technology
I am my gosh I am glued to my phone but I do
want to talk to you very quickly about Opera and
to continue the theme of three things I wanted
to talk to you today about Opera completely free
web browser I have been using and totally loving
I spend way too much time on the internet whether
it's for work or for leisure but Opera has some
great built-in features which makes my browsing
even more enjoyable there is this amazing area
feature on the sidebar which is a browser AI
where you can get instant information so if
you've already forgotten how order stegosaurus
is no worries ping it in the chat and you will
get instant clear answers and you can also
create pin boards so you can keep all of
your replies together by topic this is great
for studying or maybe researching a holiday
when browsing you can also select any word on
a web page and ARIA will support on explaining
that word translating it or Explore More on that
topic now I often have over 50 tabs open but with
tab Islands this helps you stay organized as you
can group tabs by topic so you can have say 10
Hotel tabs open they can be organized together
five shopping tabs these can be condensed into
their own clear colorcoded tabs it makes me feel
super organized and also allows me to switch off
from work mode very quickly back into Leisure
weekend mode so check out the link to download
today back to the museum a the blue whale is
temporary closed damn let's go through the
mammal section is getting busy I to find these
things so creepy when I was a kid cross sections
oh look at the little platypus they have some
very interesting animals in here and then they
have a bit of info obviously on where they live
and the mammal history and obviously lots of
extinct things as well this is a dipo Toon from
Australia I'm on the hunt for the dodo I always
remember seeing the dodo when I was a kid o look
at this little thing oh Indian flying Fox that
is terrifying it's massive it's bigger than the
map there's a lot more in here than I remember
oh my God look at the size of this bear and a
mildly terrifying Cola bear with a lot of upset
children now we're blitzing the ground floor I
want to go across to like the volcano section
that will be cool and then we'll make our way up
and I think the dodo is up on the second floor
and we will continue up the absolutely
freaking incredible grand staircase my
gosh but before we get to the volcano section
it looks like we're going to walk through the
green section I do like the color coding
which is fossils insects and all sorts of
creepy cwes oo look at the size of these
fossils this is absolutely incredible I
remember this area as a kid and it's nice get
a little bit daylight I've just passing the
T-Rex restaurant I've never been I'm a bit
skeptical miss a bit of restaurants being
inside of um actual museums I think there's a
lot of good places to eat in South Kensington
but there we go a little bit of a snapshot of
the menu if you want a salad a few options for
you there it's pretty standard restaurant
prices and then a bit on the kids there
you can see some prices but I'm going to be
a little bit nosy cuz you know what I'm like
it looks like just kind of a
slightly themed restaurant I
think it's clutching straws a little bit
saying that it's themed it's just like a
cafe and at the time of filming this the
wildlife photographer of the year is on
which is a paid exhibition I've been a few times
it's okay um but look at this an extinct vaml
oh my gosh I can't pronounce any of these
things guys I think a lot of the time the
font's actually too small in these museums so
yeah and a a megatherium americanum let's go
check out the birds oh my gosh there is huge
I'm actually a little bit scared I find some
birds a bit scary feel like watching Alfred
Hitchcock birds as a kid probably wasn't the
best idea God these vultures are massive
I found the dodos there's a couple of them
there's actually a whole section on kind of
the evolution of what we thought they were
in the different interpretations but sadly it
says they wen't extinct in the late 17 century
this hummingbird display has creeped me
out since a kid yes hundreds and hundreds
every single type of hummingbird I think is in
here gosh I remember these from a school trip
I think we had to draw them at one point but
yeah they've got a whole section the anatomy
of different birds feathers and a lot of
bird heads these they have this model of
a Stegosaurus it's amazing and the glow but
the escalator is sharp it's being repaired
get on with it then my gosh I get very annoyed
when things are closed in museums but yeah it
usually spins slightly as you go up I think
it still does but it gives quite an amazing
journey I don't think I have ever been in here
let's have a look oh this is like a whole full
section let me see what we can find there go the
oldest tooth 3.5 million years old guys why does
my camera do that with the with the light if
I film in 24 frames and 30 frames it makes no
difference or is it just the lights I don't
know male chimpanzee all the way through to
human that's pretty cool I mean my PT would
argue that my posture is a little bit like
that half the time and they even made bowls and
cups out of skulls oh gosh from 14,700 years ago
there are definitely quite a lot of scared kids
in this Museum some of it is a bit freaky though
I guess ooh look at this burial from Israel
60,000 years old I do like this they have like
a found skull or a model of a a found skull
and then what they think that person looked
like crazy like how do they know so this is
50 technically 50,000 years old wow it kind
of creeps me out a little it I like that bit
it's just like a little Corridor but it's got
quite a bit in it but yeah I think there are
quite a few scared children here I guess it's
kind of creepy like I say and as we peek out
the window that's actually the VNA across the
way so this whole area in South Kensington is
known as like the museum area in London you've
got yeah the V and A Natural History Museum
um and the science museum I don't know if I
could personally cope doing all three in one
day but they're all free which is great and
they often have paid exhibitions as well well so
add it to your list after exploring the Earth we
are going to go around this red section and see I
think there's a meteorite that you can touch but
across the top of this map I definitely recommend
grabbing a map you've got kind of the main iconic
things oh yeah the giant sloth I want to see if
the giant sequa is there it was usually at the
top of the stairs but I didn't see it um but yes
and we saw the T-Rex earlier there is so much here
guys I was go for the sparkly stuff stip night
it doesn't film too well does it with the glass
but I'll try and show you some things what we do
not grow or hunt for we must take from the earth
I think some people would debate that but you
got I feel like this is like a proper geography
lesson metamorphic sedimentary and ignas rocks
I'm not going to give you a science lesson don't
worry but this is a really good one to have
a mooch around it's crazy dark in here but
they have got a whole section on gem stone it's
almost like we're in hars guys and I can never
film in the jewelry sections and then we've got
some jewelry coming up I'm actually taking ages
looking at all of this but yeah all the different
stones and collectors and how they get set I guess
Elizabeth Taylor did have a significant amount of
this part of the industry but it's pretty cool to
see all of this in the cabinets I think it's
a really nice addition it's literally cabinet
after cabinet God I wonder how much all of this
is worth and then a section objects of Desire the
stuff that you and I probably want Ruby Sapphire
emerald acarine and diamonds let's look at these
goodness it's probably not going to show very well
but they are some Whoppers I mean if you're into
rocks this is the place look at that one oh my
gosh pyite pyite this is like a something out
of a Superman movie I'm laughing because there's
another whole section of rocks down here okay you
could spend i' would say good part of three plus
hours in the whole of this museum look at that one
it looks like it's hairy mesolite and a section
on concrete but I'm a bit rocked out I think
there's only so many rocks one person could look
at um right let's look into where's the volcano
bit I think this is a little bit better than the
side Science Museum but we will maybe go to the
Science Museum in a video more rocks oh he's a
bit creepy an early plant eating Reptile from
about 250 million years ago there's so much in
here and it also highlights the things that it
says a thousand years ago humans made extinct an
extinct cat there are definitely more food places
than before so if you want to grab a sandwich or
something like that that it is mental though 615
for a bagette I mean if you're flagging you're
flagging 5 60 £ for a lemonade and a glass oh
no okay a glass bottle of water let's go
over here £3 50 it's quite expensive but
we've made it to the volcano section I can hear
it oh wow it is busy in here I just want to see
the little jiggly room they have this mockup of a
supermarket in Japan this will move this will stay
still but yes there you go you can come in and
experience like a little bit of I guess it's
just making learning a bit more enjoyable
and fun for kids what happens under the sea
on the tectonic plates what's happening
when there is an earthquake and yeah the
dangers behind it it's a pretty good um walk
through actually and even some casts from
Pompei I didn't actually go in the creepy crawly
section I'm not good with bugs okay just for like
30 seconds we have a look guys I have to say it's
I think it's 8 degrees out today it's actually
quite cold these museums are absolutely roasting
I've got such a thin jacket on everyone is like
boiling there's no air conditioning in here so
be aware spiders my least favorite maybe you
will quickly just go in here look at this number
one crawly house e let have a look I I see so it's
obviously a mockup house and then it's got all the
gross bugs which are probably maybe in your house
ew gross that is disgusting so yeah if you have a
cat the cat could pick up a flea or two all right
there we go we've got the kitchen obviously these
are not to scale beetles mites moths oh oh this
is making me itchy ew look and they've even done
the sink cabinet of crustaceans it said what's
the size of that is that it's a scale that is
horrendous that one's even bigger a giant Japanese
spider crab oh God get me out of here God this is
busy in here right let's go out it's absolutely
roasting back into the main hall let's go up the
stairs crazy busy now got a little bit more to
do we are at this green section here it
says building Nature's treasure house and
then a little bit up there but yes wow
there's so much here as I said about 20
times already they do think coming in even
for a wander around is a must going to show
you one more short look at that even
more rocks sparkly things look at the
ceiling I think this is like the extra
special stuff in here a Dodo skeleton a
rare composite skeleton of a Dodo wow and it
does say uh caused by humans to go extinct
oh these feel a bit steep I think it's
making my legs Go funny this is going
to be an epic view oh God this place is
just absolutely gorgeous I love all the
tile work yeah like I said I think it's
almost 150 years old give or take 5 six
years and the last thing that we're going
to see today is the top of these stairs
but also look at all the detail we saw
some of it outside the animals look at
this all the way up the arch incredible
oh my gosh this sequia has the age of
1,335 years goodness me I can't even get it in
the picture so that was my little tour of the
Natural History Museum here in South Kensington
and can you believe this is all free I've been
here I I think nearly 3 hours I am kind of done
put a fork in me I am done I think I need to go
and have an afternoon with no other people but
yes I would highly recommend it I think this is
probably my top three free things to do in London
especially as oh it is raining it's raining of
course it's raining we're in um but I hope you
enjoyed that video or it wasn't for everyone but
I do go to museums quite often I think I went
to an exhibition in last week's video but like
I said at the beginning we're at the beginning of
our countdown to Spring hopefully one day I don't
have to worry ja in a video but make sure you are
subscribed because what we're doing Tuesday we
have something new and different on the channel
we're going to be doing a £1 shopping challenge
at certain stores so stick around 600 p.m. on
Tuesday and then Friday kind of a normal upload
what AM we going to be doing going and see the
shops see what's out and about things to do in
London maybe we'll do some more museums I don't
know including actually we have an afternoon tea
book do remember to check out opera again that's
free so go and have a look and come and say hi
over on Instagram and yeah I will see you in a
few days time make sure you're subscribed bye
[Music]